Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're going back to the movies.
今天我们要回到电影话题。
That's right.
没错。
We've got a great lesson today and I'm really excited about this dialogue.
今天我们有一堂很棒的课，我对这段对话非常兴奋。
I think it's fantastic.
我觉得它太棒了。
We have an original EnglishPod production of a movie trailer.
我们有一个原创的EnglishPod制作的电影预告片。
So what is a movie trailer?
那么什么是电影预告片？
Well, whenever you go to the cinema, before the movie starts, you have previews of upcoming
嗯，每当你去电影院，在电影开始之前，你会看到即将上映电影的预览。
movies.
电影。
So it's an advertisement for a future movie.
所以它是未来电影的广告。
Exactly.
正是。
So that's a movie trailer and that's what we're bringing you today.
所以那就是电影预告片，今天我们带给你的就是它。
A lot of great language you'll commonly hear in action movies.
很多你在动作片中常听到的精彩语言。
Right.
对。
So let's start with vocabulary preview.
那么我们从词汇预览开始。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
We have one word today, possess.
今天我们有一个词：possess。
Possess.
Possess。
So when you possess something, you have it.
所以当你拥有某物时，你就拥有它。
It's in your possession.
它在你的掌控之中。
Simple.
简单。
You have it, right?
你拥有它，对吧？
Yep.
是的。
So in this dialogue, our actors possess something very important.
所以在这段对话中，我们的演员拥有一些非常重要的东西。
So let's listen to the dialogue for the first time and it's going to be a little bit fast
那么让我们第一次听这段对话，它会有点快。
and a little bit difficult to understand.
有点难懂。
But don't worry, we'll come back and explain all of the key language later.
但别担心，我们稍后会回来解释所有关键语言。
Look!
看！
In a digital world, even the strongest must fight for survival.
在一个数字世界里，即使是最强者也必须为生存而战。
Two people possess a secret so valuable, so powerful, they have to defend it at all costs.
两个人拥有一个如此珍贵、如此强大的秘密，他们必须不惜一切代价保护它。
I don't care where they are.
我不在乎他们在哪里。
I don't care what it takes.
我不在乎要付出什么代价。
You find them and bring them to me.
你找到他们，把他们带到我面前。
They only had one chance and their chance was to fight back.
他们只有一次机会，而他们的机会就是反击。
You want to play rough?
你想来硬的？
Say hello to my little friend.
跟我的小朋友打个招呼。
With a little help from the governor.
在州长的帮助下。
Listen to me.
听我说。
We have to go.
我们得走了。
Listen to me, we have to get them out of there, no matter what.
听我说，无论如何我们都要把他们救出来。
Nothing will prevent them from doing their job.
没有什么能阻止他们完成工作。
Double the action.
双倍动作。
Get down!
趴下！
Triple the excitement.
三倍刺激。
Get down again!
再趴下！
This summer, nothing will stand in their way.
这个夏天，没有什么能阻挡他们。
I'm gonna make them run off again.
我会让他们再次逃跑。
Two hosts, one podcast.
两位主持人，一个播客。
EnglishPod.
EnglishPod。
Coming to a theater near you.
即将在您附近的影院上映。
Wow, so it sounds like a really good movie.
哇，听起来真是一部好电影。
I know, when's it coming out?
我知道，什么时候上映？
I think in 2015.
我想是2015年。
Okay, I'll put that in my calendar.
好的，我会记在日历上。
Okay, let's take a look at the vocabulary we saw in this dialogue in Language Takeaway.
好的，让我们看看在语言要点环节中看到的词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
In Language Takeaway today, we have three words.
今天的语言要点，我们有三个词。
What's our first one?
第一个是什么？
Survival.
生存。
Well, survival is continuing to live even in really hard times.
嗯，生存是指在艰难时期继续活下去。
It comes from the verb to survive.
它来自动词 survive。
Right, so survival is the noun form.
对，所以 survival 是名词形式。
Right, so maybe you are lost in the jungle and you have to fight for survival.
对，比如你迷失在丛林中，必须为生存而战。
Right, you have to try to survive.
对，你必须努力活下去。
Okay, our next word, defend.
好的，下一个词，defend。
Defend.
防御。
So let's listen to some examples of defend so you can understand the meaning.
让我们听一些例子来理解 defend 的意思。
Example one.
例子一。
We have to defend the castle.
我们必须保卫城堡。
The army is trying to kill the king.
军队试图杀死国王。
Example two.
例子二。
The soldiers defended the base in a difficult battle.
士兵们在一次艰苦的战斗中保卫了基地。
Example three.
例子三。
These new machine guns will defend us.
这些新机枪将保护我们。
So basically it's to protect, right?
所以基本上就是保护，对吧？
Right, to protect from something that is really harmful.
对，保护免受真正有害的东西的伤害。
Okay, so you would defend your children, you would defend your...
好的，所以你会保护你的孩子，你会保护你的……
Your house.
你的房子。
Or your castle.
或者你的城堡。
Your dog, your cat.
你的狗，你的猫。
Okay, and our last word on Language Takeaway, rough.
好的，我们语言摘录的最后一个词，rough。
Rough.
Rough。
R-O-U-G-H, rough.
R-O-U-G-H，rough。
Right, it's got that uff sound.
对，它有一个“uff”的音。
So it basically means...
所以它基本上意思是……
So when something is rough, it's a little bit violent.
所以当某物很rough时，它有点暴力。
And hard.
而且硬。
Hard.
硬。
For example, boxing is a rough sport.
例如，拳击是一项粗暴的运动。
Or hockey is also a rough sport.
或者冰球也是一项粗暴的运动。
Exactly.
没错。
So you have rough sports or maybe even a person can be a little bit rough.
所以有粗暴的运动，甚至一个人也可能有点粗暴。
Yes, or that person can play rough.
是的，或者那个人可以玩得很粗暴。
Play rough, exactly.
玩得很粗暴，没错。
So rough.
所以是rough。
Okay, so we're ready to listen to our dialogue again.
好的，我们准备好再听一遍对话了。
And this time it'll be a little bit slower so you can understand the language a little
这次会慢一点，这样你能更清楚地理解语言。
bit more clearly.
In a digital world, even the strongest must fight for survival.
在数字世界里，即使是最强者也必须为生存而战。
Two people possess a secret so valuable, so powerful, they have to defend it at all costs.
两个人拥有一个如此珍贵、如此强大的秘密，他们必须不惜一切代价保护它。
I don't care where they are.
我不在乎他们在哪里。
I don't care what it takes.
我不在乎要付出什么代价。
You find them and bring them to me.
找到他们，带他们来见我。
They only had one chance.
他们只有一次机会。
And their chance was to fight back.
他们的机会就是反击。
Okay, you want to play rough?
好吧，你想玩硬的？
Say hello to my little friend.
跟我的小朋友打个招呼吧。
With a little help from the governor.
在州长的一点帮助下。
Listen to me, we have to get them out of there, no matter what.
听我说，我们必须把他们弄出来，无论如何。
Nothing will prevent them from doing their job.
没有什么能阻止他们完成工作。
Double the action.
加倍行动。
Get down.
趴下。
Triple the excitement.
三倍刺激。
Get down again.
再趴下。
This summer, nothing will stand in their way.
这个夏天，没有什么能阻挡他们。
I'm going to make him an offer he can't refuse.
我要给他一个他无法拒绝的条件。
Two hosts, one podcast.
两位主持人，一个播客。
EnglishPod, coming to a theater near you.
EnglishPod，即将在你附近的影院上映。
So we saw some interesting phrases in this dialogue.
我们在对话中看到了一些有趣的短语。
Let's take a look at them in Fluency Builder.
让我们在流利度构建器中看看它们。
The first phrase that we saw, at all costs.
我们看到的第一个短语是 at all costs。
At all costs.
不惜一切代价。
So let's listen to some examples before we explain at all costs.
在解释 at all costs 之前，让我们先听一些例子。
Example one.
例子一。
I'll protect my kids at all costs.
我会不惜一切代价保护我的孩子。
Example two.
例子二。
We have to get this project done at all costs.
我们必须不惜一切代价完成这个项目。
Example three.
例子三。
You find those criminals at all costs.
你们要不惜一切代价找到那些罪犯。
Well, if you're going to protect your kids at all costs,
嗯，如果你要不惜一切代价保护你的孩子，
you're going to protect them even if it's really hard.
即使非常困难，你也会保护他们。
Right, it doesn't matter how hard it is or what you have to do.
对，不管有多难或者你必须做什么。
Exactly.
没错。
You'll do it at all costs.
你会不惜一切代价去做。
Now let's take a look at our second phrase for Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看流利度构建器中的第二个短语。
And it's very similar to at all costs.
它和 at all costs 非常相似。
Yeah, really similar.
是的，非常相似。
No matter what.
无论如何。
For example, I'm going to go on vacation no matter what my boss says.
例如，不管老板说什么，我都要去度假。
Nothing's going to stop you.
没什么能阻止你。
If he says no, I'm still going on vacation.
如果他说不行，我还是会去度假。
And I'm going to protect my kids no matter what.
而且我会无论如何保护我的孩子。
Exactly.
没错。
No matter what.
无论如何。
I don't have kids though.
不过我没有孩子。
But you will protect them no matter what.
但无论如何你都会保护他们。
If I had them.
如果我有孩子的话。
OK.
好的。
And our last phrase, stand in their way.
我们最后一个短语是，挡他们的路。
Stand in their way.
挡他们的路。
So let's listen to some examples of stand in someone's way.
那么我们来听一些关于“挡某人的路”的例子。
And then we'll come back and explain it.
然后我们再回来解释。
Example one.
例子一。
Don't let anything stand in the way of your goals.
不要让任何事情阻碍你实现目标。
Example two.
例子二。
I'm going to find that guy and nothing is going to stand in my way.
我要找到那个人，没有什么能阻挡我。
Example three.
例子三。
I don't care what happens.
我不在乎发生什么。
I'm going to get that money and you better not stand in my way.
我一定要拿到那笔钱，你最好别挡我的路。
So when something stands in your way, it's.
所以当某件事挡了你的路，它就是在……
It's preventing you from reaching your goal.
它阻止你达到目标。
From reaching your goal, right.
阻止你达到目标，对吧。
But we can also have somebody standing in your way physically.
但也可以指有人从物理上挡你的路。
Like really you're standing close to me and I can't pass through the door.
比如你真的站得很近，我无法通过门。
Right.
对。
So maybe the person is at the door and it's standing in my way.
所以可能那个人站在门口，挡住了我的路。
I can't go in.
我进不去。
Yeah.
是的。
OK.
好的。
But here we're not really talking about a real thing, right.
但这里我们说的不是真实的东西，对吧。
That you can touch.
你可以触摸到的东西。
Right.
对。
It's more of some obstacle that's preventing you from reaching your goals
它更像是一种阻碍你达成目标的东西。
or from doing what you want to do.
或者阻止你做想做的事。
Yeah.
是的。
So now we can listen to our dialogue again.
那么现在我们可以再听一遍对话。
And now you can understand these words that we've just talked about.
现在你能理解我们刚刚讨论的这些词了。
Look.
看。
In a digital world, even the strongest must fight for survival.
在数字世界里，即使是最强者也必须为生存而战。
Two people possess a secret so valuable, so powerful,
两个人拥有一个如此珍贵、如此强大的秘密，
they have to defend it at all costs.
他们必须不惜一切代价保护它。
I don't care where they are.
我不在乎他们在哪里。
I don't care what it takes.
我不在乎要付出什么代价。
You find them and bring them to me.
你找到他们，把他们带到我面前。
They only had one chance and their chance was to fight back.
他们只有一次机会，那就是反击。
You want to play rough?
你想来硬的？
Say hello to my little friend.
跟我的小朋友打个招呼吧。
With a little help from the governor.
在州长的帮助下。
Listen to me.
听我说。
We have to get them out of there.
我们必须把他们弄出来。
No matter what.
无论如何。
Nothing will prevent them from doing their job.
没有什么能阻止他们完成工作。
Double the action.
双倍的动作。
Get down.
趴下。
Triple the excitement.
三倍的刺激。
Get down again.
再趴下。
This summer, nothing will stand in their way.
这个夏天，没有什么能阻挡他们。
I'm going to make them an offer again, people.
我要再给他们一个提议，各位。
Two hosts.
两位主持人。
One podcast.
一个播客。
EnglishPod.
EnglishPod。
Coming to a theatre near you.
即将来到你附近的影院。
I know that you're a big movie fan, right?
我知道你是个大影迷，对吧？
Yeah, I'm a big movie fan.
是的，我是个超级影迷。
I usually watch maybe three or five movies a week.
我通常每周看三到五部电影。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
Wow.
哇。
How do you like the movie?
你觉得这部电影怎么样？
I love the movie.
我很喜欢这部电影。
You like the movie?
你喜欢这部电影吗？
I love the movie.
我很喜欢这部电影。
Really?
真的吗？
Many students of English like to watch movies as a way to improve their English.
很多英语学习者喜欢通过看电影来提高英语水平。
That's one of the best ways to learn English is through songs and movies.
通过歌曲和电影学习英语是最好的方法之一。
What do you think are some useful movies that people can watch to practice English?
你觉得有哪些有用的电影可以让人用来练习英语？
Well, I would recommend children's movies.
嗯，我会推荐儿童电影。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, they have simple vocabulary, but they have very common language.
是的，它们的词汇简单，但语言很常用。
And also, what's happening in the movie is very easy to understand and to follow.
而且，电影里发生的事情很容易理解和跟上。
So you can see the action and then hear the word.
所以你可以看到动作，然后听到单词。
Exactly.
没错。
So if you like to watch movies, rent a DVD or go buy a DVD, watch it in the original language with English subtitles.
所以如果你喜欢看电影，租一张DVD或者去买一张DVD，用原声加英文字幕看。
So you should watch it in English.
所以你应该看英文版的。
With English subtitles.
带英文字幕。
Yeah, and what are subtitles?
嗯，什么是字幕？
Subtitles are the words that you see at the bottom of the screen that translate what the people are saying.
字幕就是你在屏幕底部看到的文字，用来翻译人们说的话。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah, that's the best thing to do.
是的，这是最好的做法。
Try that exercise.
试试这个练习。
If you have a pen and paper with you, it's much better.
如果你随身带着笔和纸，效果会更好。
You can pause the movie, write down a word you don't understand, and then maybe review it later.
你可以暂停电影，写下你不懂的单词，然后稍后复习。
That's a really good tip.
这真是个好建议。
I always tell my students that they should watch movies, listen to music, read the newspaper, and write down at least five new words or phrases a week.
我总是告诉我的学生，他们应该看电影、听音乐、读报纸，并且每周至少写下五个新单词或短语。
Yeah, yeah, it's a really good exercise and you'll improve a lot.
是的，是的，这是个很好的练习，你会进步很多。
Yes.
是的。
So everyone, we want you to go out and watch a movie in English.
所以各位，我们希望你们出去看一部英文电影。
Turn on the subtitles and write down some new vocabulary.
打开字幕，写下一些新词汇。
Exactly.
没错。
And if you have any comments or questions or maybe even suggestions, you can come to our website at EnglishPod.com and leave them in our community page.
如果你有任何评论、问题，甚至建议，你可以访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，在我们的社区页面留言。
Marco and I are always around to help you and we love to hear about what you're learning and what movies you're watching.
Marco 和我随时都在帮助你，我们很乐意了解你在学什么以及你在看什么电影。
Exactly.
没错。
So we're out of time today.
今天我们时间到了。
We'll see you guys next time.
我们下次再见。
Until then, it's...
在那之前，我们……
Goodbye.
再见。